Alexander Nieves

Full-Stack Web Developer

paulalexander.nieves@gmail.com 959922344

LinkedIn | GitHub

For the past 5 years, I have been working in the fields of mining and environmental impact. This led me to discover a passion for data analysis and planning, which can have a great influence in decision-making. To dive deeper into this area, I decided to develop tech skills; that way, I can combine my previous experience with the latest technological advances.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavascriptHTMLCSSGit / GithubRubyRailsReactAdvanced ExcelNodePythonRelational DatabasesR Language

EXPERIENCE

OEFA Lima, Peru

State organization dedicated to the protection of the environment

Supervisor

• Collaborated with the engineering team by gathering, processing and analyzing data to create and maintain dashboards in

 Collaborated with the engineering team by gathering, processing and analyzing data to create and maintain dashboards in order to keep track of the digitization process, which allowed to streamline and evidence organization status and internal processes

SIMSA/ PAN AMERICAN Junin, Peru

Mining Company

intern 2019 – 2020

 In charge of planning and maintaining data sets in order to analyze and process information needed for decision-making regarding company planning.

GORE AREQUIPA Junin, Peru

Regional authority in charge of supervising a small mining sector

Analyst

Identified key important values about the mining sector by analyzing reports which let authorities keep track of mining operations

• Analyzed data and created statistical models using basic programming to contribute to mining operation tracking.

EDUCATION

Codeable (www.codeable.la)

Lima, Peru

2017-2018

Intensive full-stack web development education program (full-time, 6 months)

2022

CIBERTEC/Institute Lima, Peru

Data Architecture

2020 - 202

UNSA/University

Mining Engineering

Arequipa, Peru
2011 – 2015

ADDITIONAL

• Languages: native Spanish, proficient English.

Alexander Nieves

Desarrollador Full-Stack

paulalexander.nieves@gmail.com 959922344

LinkedIn | GitHub

Durante los últimos 5 años, he estado trabajando en las áreas de minería e impacto ambiental. Esto me llevó a descubrir una pasión por el análisis de datos y la planificación, que pueden tener una gran influencia en la toma de decisiones. Para profundizar más en esta área, decidí desarrollar habilidades técnicas en programación y así poder combinarla con mi experiencia previa.

HABILIDADES TÉCNICAS

Javascript	HTML	CSS	Git / Github
Ruby	Rails	React	Excel avanzado
Node	Python	Bases de datos relacionales	Lenguaje R

EXPERIENCIA

OEFA/ BUREAU VERITAS Lima, Peru

Organismo dedicado a la protección del medio ambiente y monitoreo ambiental Supervisor

2022

• Colaboré con el equipo de ingeniería recopilando, procesando y analizando datos para crear y mantener dashboards con el fin de realizar un seguimiento del proceso de digitalización, lo que permitió agilizar y evidenciar el estado de la organización y los procesos internos.

SIMSA/ PAN AMERICAN Junin, Peru

Compañía Minera

Practicas 2019 – 2020

 Colaboré en los procesos de planificación, realice mantenimiento de datasets, analizando y procesando la información necesaria para la toma de decisiones.

GOBIERNO REGIONAL DE AREQUIPA

Junin, Peru

Autoridad regional a cargo de la supervisión en la sector de la pequeña minería Analista

2017-2018

- Se identificó factores clave en el sector minero materializado en la confección de informes que permitió a las autoridades realizar un seguimiento de las operaciones mineras.
- Se analizó datos utilizando programación básica para contribuir al seguimiento de la planificación mensual realizada.

EDUCACIÓN

Codeable (www.codeable.la)

Lima, Peru

Programa intensivo como Full Stack Developer (6 meses full tiempo)

2022

CIBERTEC/Instituto
Arquitectura de Datos
Lima, Peru
2020 – 2022

UNSA/Universidad Arequipa,

Peru

Ingeniería de Minas 2011 – 2015

ADICIONAL

• Lenguajes: Nativo en Español, Inglés Intermedio.